<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marthin Satrya Pasaribu</title>
    <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marthin Satrya Pasaribu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://marthinpsrb.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux Policy Routing - Introduction</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/linux-policy-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/linux-policy-routing/</guid>
      <description>Policy routing actually allows us a great deal of flexibility in how we direct traffic out of a Linux host. There are a couple parts involved in policy routing:
 Policy routing tables: Routes added to the system without a routing table specified go to the main table, not the default table. Linux comes with three default.  Local (cannot be modified or default) Main Default   Policy routing rules: Linux comes with three rules, one for each of the default routing tables  When we’re trying to used policy routing for our purpose we need to do three things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy On Write (COW) in SWIFT</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/copy-on-write-cow-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/copy-on-write-cow-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>What is Copy on Write?  Copy on Write (CoW or COW), sometimes referred to as implicit sharing or shadowing is a resource-management technique used in computer programming to efficiently implement a “duplicate” or “copy” operation on modifiable resources. If a resource duplicated but not modified it is not necessary to create a new resource. The resource can be shared between the copy and the original. Source: Wikipedia
 Copy on write is a common computing technique that helps increase performance when copying structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocol Why you’re important??</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/protocol-why-youre-really-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/protocol-why-youre-really-important/</guid>
      <description>This is only short blog, why we need protocol(Swift) – Interface(Java). It’s just come to my mind suddenly:
First what’s the protocol in Swift?
 A protocol defines a blueprint of methods, properties, and other requirements that suit a particular task or piece of functionality
  Source: https://docs.swift.org/swift-book/LanguageGuide/Protocols.html
 Second thing:
Why we need you Protocol, What are you doing so we can’t work without you?
To answer this question, I find one example that I think it can describe why we need protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegate Pattern on iOS Swift</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/delegate-pattern-on-ios-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/delegate-pattern-on-ios-swift/</guid>
      <description>Before you read this article, it’s mandatory to you understand protocol.
Delegate pattern can help you to handle the same task to a different module. Let’s say you build an app, but you want to track or write logging of the user and insert it to local storage. Delegate pattern can help you to make it easily and not redundant.
The main benefit of delegating certain decisions and behaviors to a type’s owner is that it becomes much easier to support multiple use cases without having to create massive types that themselves need to account for all those use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocol in Swift</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/protocol-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/protocol-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>What is Protocol?  According to Apple Documentation–
  A protocol defines a blueprint of methods, properties, and other requirements that suit a particular task or piece of functionality. The protocol can then be adopted by a class, structure, or enumeration to provide an actual implementation of those requirements. Any type that satisfies the requirements of a protocol is said to conform to that protocol. In addition to specifying requirements that conforming types must implement, you can extend a protocol to implement some of these requirements or to implement additional functionality that conforming types can take advantage of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Pattern – Clean Architecture</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/architecture-pattern-clean-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/architecture-pattern-clean-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Architecture Pattern:  Reusable solution A “pattern” has been defined as: “an idea that has been useful in one practical context and will probably be useful in others Help to easy to test the code  Good Architecture? What is it? Good Architecture:
 A balanced distribution of responsibilities for all entity and specific roles Testability, it means the code easy and can be tested Ease of use, and a low maintenance cost  By Uncle Bob:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn Swift ?</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/how-to-learn-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/how-to-learn-swift/</guid>
      <description>Source: https://www.pinterest.com/pin/323766660691724412/
  Swift was released in 2014 as open-source language. I started learning Swift around 2 weeks ago. There are a lot of ways to go about learning Swift, and the lesson can be done on your own time.
New Programming language, it means a new experience. For me, most of them have the same concept but have a different approach. Like in Java for collection type they have Array, HashMap, LinkedList, ArrayList, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Driven Development</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/model-driven-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/model-driven-development/</guid>
      <description>A metaphor for Model Driven Engineering
  Model driven development is one of methodology for software development that focuses on creating and exploiting domain models. If i can make the analogy, programmer as contractor.
Imagine you’re a good contractor in your city, and someone want you to build a house for him. Actually, he just give you the land area and the type of home like how many rooms are there, need parking area etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Programming Notes (Part 3)</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge isn’t stable. It changes—often rapidly. Your understanding of a requirement may change following a meeting with the client. All this instability means that we spend a large part of our time in maintenance mode, reorganizing and reexpressing the knowledge in our systems.
  Maintenance is not a discrete activity, but a routine part of the entire development process.
  The alternative is to have the same thing expressed in two or more places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Programming Notes (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Within the overall structure of a project there is always room for individuality and craftsmanship. This is particularly true given the current state of software engineering. Our engineering may seem as archaic as the techniques used by medieval cathedral builders seem to today’s civil engineers, while our craftsmanship will still be honored. Software engineering technic will always change, but what were you done in the past it will still be honored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Programming Notes (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Building Your Portfolio To be successful in your career, you must manage your knowledge portfolio using these same guidelines:
  Invest Regularly Just as in financial investing, you must invest in your knowledge portfolio regularly. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s just a small amount, the habit itself is as important as the sums Diversify
  Diversify The more different things you know, the more valuable you. The more technologies you are comfortable with, the better you will be able to adjust to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Programming Notes (Part 4)</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Easy Development or Easy Maintenance?
The trade-off is extendibility and maintenance. While the code for parsing a “real” language may be harder to write, it will be much easier for people to understand, and to extend in the future with new features and functionality. Building Your Portfolio
How Accurate Is Accurate Enough?
To some extent(tingkat), all answers are estimates.
t’s just that some are more accurate than others. So the first question you have to ask yourself when someone asks you for an estimate is the context in which your answer will be taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Programming Notes (Part 5)</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/pragmatic-programming-notes-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Pragmatic Paranoia You Can’t Write Perfect Software Did that hurt? It shouldn’t. Accept it as an axiom of life. Embrace it. Celebrate it. Because perfect software doesn’t exist. We are constantly interfacing with other people’s code—code that might not live up to our high standards—and dealing with inputs that may or may not be valid.
So we are taught to code defensively. If there’s any doubt, we validate all information we’re given.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Companies Go Public?</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/why-companies-go-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/why-companies-go-public/</guid>
      <description>There are two basic reasons. Technically an IPO is just another way to raise money, but this time from millions of regular people. Through an IPO a company can sell stocks on the stock market and anyone can buy them. Since anyone can buy you can likely sell a lot of stock right away rather than go to individual investors and ask them to invest. So it sounds like an easier way to get money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC – Remote Procedure Call</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/grpc-remote-procedure-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/grpc-remote-procedure-call/</guid>
      <description>Now, i wanna share about gRPC. Before we go to deeply, the first question is , what is it? From the real website of gRPC (grpc.io) the meaning of gRPC:
gRPC is a modern, open source remote procedure call (RPC) framework that can run anywhere. It enables client and server applications to communicate transparently, and makes it easier to build connected systems. The next question is, what does gRPC stands for?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Feedback</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/star-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/star-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Di sebuah desa yang sedikit agak lumayan mungkin terpencil di kabupaten apoangkecek hiduplah seorang anak yang bernama Ucok. Ucok merupakan seseorang anak yang sedikit pemalu walaupun terkadang malu maluin. Ucok merupakan lulusan dari universitas ternama di kabupaten nya versi POBOX. Ucok sangat jarang aktif berbicara di kelas semasa kuliah karena memiliki sifat yang tidak suka diperhatikan orang banyak.
Ucok juga tipe orang yang tidak mudah bergaul dengan orang orang baru baru.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Perspective</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/coding-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/coding-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Deriti is currently a great chef will share how to cook fried rice to all of you. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at what Deriti said in this story:
Before you cook fried rice please complete this tools and ingredients
Tools:
 Stoves Cooking spoon Pan  Ingredients:
 plate white rice Garlic 2 cloves Sweet soy sauce 2 tablespoon Tomato sauce 1 tablespoon Sambal sauce 1 tablespoon Oyster sauce 1 tablespoon Salt 1 tablespoon Pepper powder ½ tablespoon Chicken flavored broth 1/2 tablespoon Leeks 1 stalk Chicken eggs 1 grain Shredded chicken 2 tablespoon 1 chicken sausage Margarine or cooking oil 3 tablespoon  How to cook fried rice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to solve cannot access root Ubuntu Server</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/how-to-solve-cannot-access-root-ubuntu-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/how-to-solve-cannot-access-root-ubuntu-server/</guid>
      <description> masuk recovery chown root:root /usr/bin/sudo &amp;amp;&amp;amp; chmod 4755 /usr/bin/sudo untuk perbaiki sudo chmod 644 /usr/lib/sudo/sudoers.so chown -R root /usr/lib/sudo chown root:root /etc/sudoers chmod 0440 /etc/sudoers adduser adminapibkkbn sudo (reboot ke hard drive) sudo apt-get remove –purge openssh-server &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get install openssh-server  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Introduction</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/linux-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/linux-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Linux is a computer operating system. An operating system consists of the software that manages your computer and lets you run application on it. The features that make up Linux and similar computer operating systems include the following.
 Detecting and preparing hardware  When you turn on your computer, the Linux system will boot up and loads the software (drivers and modules) needed to access those particular hardware devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Funding Works in Startup</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/how-funding-works-in-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/how-funding-works-in-startup/</guid>
      <description>Startups looking for angel investors or venture capital (VC) absolutely need an exit strategy because investors require it. The exit is what gives them a return. Exit strategies related to startup funding are quite often misunderstood: The “exit” in exit strategy is for the money, not the startup founders or small business owners. The company brings in money and the investors get money out. So startups looking for angel investors or venture capital (VC) absolutely need an exit strategy because investors require it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction Blog</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post in this blog. So i would like to thank you for people who give advise to me. Nice to meet you in this blog and enjoy my story. Bye the way my name is Marthin Satrya Pasaribu, and i from Computer science background.
In this blog, may be i will post about startup and Software Technology, I will share about my experience in startup “You don’t need much money to give something to others but you just need desire and sincerity” — MSP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Blog Story</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/old-blog-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/old-blog-story/</guid>
      <description>Old Blog
Tentang Penulis &amp;quot; Sebelumnya saya sebagai admin meminta maaf kepada pembaca karena belum dapat meng-update berita di blog ini. Berhubung sibuk kuliah dan masih banyak tugas yang menumpuk jadi mohon di maklumi.Pertama saya ingin memperkenalkan diri dulu. Nama lengkap saya Marthin Satrya Pasaribu seorang mahasiswa di Institut Teknologi Del (IT Del) yang dulunya bernama Politeknik Informatika Del (PI Del).Berdarah batak Toba asli gak ada campuran nya. Cita-cita saya adalah menjadi seorang technopreneurship yaitu membuat sebuah perusahaan yang bergerak di bidang IT, dan mempekerjakan banyak karyawan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/startup/</guid>
      <description>What is startup? Before i explain my opinion about definition of startup. I want to share my first story when build my first startup OnanOnan.com. My future goal is become a success enterpreneur and build social company.
In my mind the first opinion about startup is start a new small company, get a revenue, there is a CEO, CTO etc. That&amp;rsquo;s my first opinion about startup . So, the next question when your company is not called startup anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello there,
My name is Marthin
I was born in Sibolga, Indonesia, a very small town in North Sumatera Province, Indonesia. I have informatics engineering background from IT Del in Sitoluama, Laguboti.
When I graduated from high school, I had absolutely no interest in computer science and have plan to take mechanical engineering to continue my studies. But one of my family member, share a bit about mobile apps and how we got money from these applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/contact/</guid>
      <description> On Twitter: @marthinpsrb Mail: marthinpsrb at gmail dot com Linkedin: Marthin Satrya Pasaribu Don&amp;rsquo;t try to find me on facebook Don&amp;rsquo;t try to find me on instagram Don&amp;rsquo;t try to find me on friendster  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First snippet</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/snippets/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/snippets/first/</guid>
      <description>This content is in snippets/first/index.md
pwd </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second snippet</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/snippets/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/snippets/second/</guid>
      <description>This content is in snippets/second/index.md
ls -la </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
