<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>marthinpsrb on Marthin Satrya Pasaribu</title>
    <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/authors/marthinpsrb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in marthinpsrb on Marthin Satrya Pasaribu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://marthinpsrb.com/authors/marthinpsrb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux Introduction</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/linux-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/linux-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Linux is a computer operating system. An operating system consists of the software that manages your computer and lets you run application on it. The features that make up Linux and similar computer operating systems include the following.
 Detecting and preparing hardware  When you turn on your computer, the Linux system will boot up and loads the software (drivers and modules) needed to access those particular hardware devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Funding Works in Startup</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/how-funding-works-in-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/how-funding-works-in-startup/</guid>
      <description>Startups looking for angel investors or venture capital (VC) absolutely need an exit strategy because investors require it. The exit is what gives them a return. Exit strategies related to startup funding are quite often misunderstood: The “exit” in exit strategy is for the money, not the startup founders or small business owners. The company brings in money and the investors get money out. So startups looking for angel investors or venture capital (VC) absolutely need an exit strategy because investors require it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction Blog</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post in this blog. So i would like to thank you for people who give advise to me. Nice to meet you in this blog and enjoy my story. Bye the way my name is Marthin Satrya Pasaribu, and i from Computer science background.
In this blog, may be i will post about startup and Software Technology, I will share about my experience in startup “You don’t need much money to give something to others but you just need desire and sincerity” — MSP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Blog Story</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/old-blog-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/old-blog-story/</guid>
      <description>Old Blog
Tentang Penulis &amp;quot; Sebelumnya saya sebagai admin meminta maaf kepada pembaca karena belum dapat meng-update berita di blog ini. Berhubung sibuk kuliah dan masih banyak tugas yang menumpuk jadi mohon di maklumi.Pertama saya ingin memperkenalkan diri dulu. Nama lengkap saya Marthin Satrya Pasaribu seorang mahasiswa di Institut Teknologi Del (IT Del) yang dulunya bernama Politeknik Informatika Del (PI Del).Berdarah batak Toba asli gak ada campuran nya. Cita-cita saya adalah menjadi seorang technopreneurship yaitu membuat sebuah perusahaan yang bergerak di bidang IT, dan mempekerjakan banyak karyawan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup</title>
      <link>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marthinpsrb.com/posts/startup/</guid>
      <description>What is startup? Before i explain my opinion about definition of startup. I want to share my first story when build my first startup OnanOnan.com. My future goal is become a success enterpreneur and build social company.
In my mind the first opinion about startup is start a new small company, get a revenue, there is a CEO, CTO etc. That&amp;rsquo;s my first opinion about startup . So, the next question when your company is not called startup anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
